Merry Madagascar is a animation, family film directed by David Soren.
While trapped on the island of Madagascar, the Central Park Zoo escapees receive a visit
from Santa--crash landing on their territory and getting amnesia to boot!
The animals must help Santa assume his rightful place in the universe,
while King Julian laps up the opportunity for his subjects.
Alex (voice), played by Ben Stiller.
Marty (voice), played by Chris Rock.
Melman (voice), played by David Schwimmer.
Gloria (voice), played by Jada Pinkett Smith.
Maurice (voice), played by Cedric the Entertainer.
Mort (voice), played by Andy Richter.
Merry Madagascar is a Christmas special that was first broadcast on the NBC network on November 17, 2009, which starred
the characters from the film series Madagascar, and takes place sometime between the first and second film.
It is the second DreamWorks Animation Christmas special, after Shrek the Halls.
It features many of the same voices from the film, including Ben
Stiller, Chris Rock, David Schwimmer, and Jada Pinkett Smith.
The only major exception was Sacha Baron Cohen as King Julien XIII, who was replaced by Danny
Jacobs, who also voices the character on The Penguins of Madagascar TV series.
Carl Reiner provided the voice of Santa Claus.
The film explores themes of amnesia, holiday, lion, hippopotamus, giraffe.